Register of the Honduran Subject Collection, 1977-1991
Hoover Institution Archives
Honduran Subject Collection,
1977-1991
XX793
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 videotape cassette, 2 phonorecords (2.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamplets, reports, speeches, leaflets, flyers, serial issues, other printed matter, audio-visual material, relating to political conditions, elections, and civil rights in Honduras.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Honduras--Politics and government.; Elections--Honduras; Civil rights--Honduras; Honduras; Phonorecords; Video tapes
Series Description
- Subject File, 1977-1991. (Box 1-2)
  Position papers, reports, letters, printed material, speeches, leaflets, electoral material, newsletters, and miscellany
- Oversize File, 1989 (Box 3)
  Poem and electoral platform
- Audiovisual File, 1963-ca. 1989. (Record cabinet, Tape cabinet.)
  Two phonorecords and one cabinet videotape cassette entitled "A Review of the First Sentence Tape ('of the Corte Interamericano de Derechos Humanos') against a cabinet State (Honduras) for the Crime of Forced Disappearances," produced by ACAFADE (Asociacion Centroamericano Familiares de Detenidos Desaparecidos)
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1977-1991
  - General. Serial issues, miscellany, letters, clipping, bulletins, pamphlets, reports, congress proceedings, flyers, cartoons, and position statements, 1977-1991. Includes material relating to university and labor unions, political parties, and relations with the United States (Box 1., Folder 1-4)
  - Elections
    - 1985. Statutes, postion statements, pamphlets, reports, speech, leaflets, biographical material, and miscellany, 1983-1985 (Folder 5)
    - 1985 (Box 2., Folder 1)
    - 1989. Position statements, report and miscellany, 1989-1990 (Folder 2)
  - Federacion Unitaria de Trabajadores de Honduras. Position papers, letters, and newsletters, 1985-1987 (Folder 3)
  - Fuerza Universitaria Revolucionaria. Flyers, newsletters, report, and miscellany, 1984-1987 (Folder 4)
  - Human rights. Reports, charts, flyers, serial issues, clippings, 1980-1989. Includes material relating to refugees and to the Comite para la Defensa de los Derechos Humanos en Honduras (CODEH) (Folder 5)
  - United States. Reports on United States military activity and foreign policy concerning Honduras, 1987 (Folder 6)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1989.
  - Oversize File, 1989. Poem and electoral platform (Box 3.)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, ca. 1963-1987
  - Phonorecords of political campaign songs
    - "Bu Giron Presidente," performed by Mariachi Nacional, 45 r.p.m.. (Box 1., Folder 1)
    - "Viva Oscar Mejia Arelliano" and "Partido Liberal," 45 r.p.m. (Folder 2)
  - One videotape cassette entitled "A Review of the First Sentence ('of the Corte Interamericano de Derechos Humanos') against a State (Honduras) for the Crime of Forced Disappearances," produced by ACAFADE (Asociacion Centroamericano Familiares de Detenidos Desaparecidos) (Box 2.)